Previously on Transformers: Prime
在上一集里
Optimus has reverted to his pre-Prime state: Orion Pax.
擎天柱回到了成为领袖之前的状态： 奥利安・派克斯
The Key-card! What does it do?
钥匙芯片！它是做什么用的？
It grants access to Vector Sigma,
用来启动魔力神球
an ancient source of mystical power.
它是一种神秘力量的古老源泉
On Cybertron.
在塞博特恩
When we stormed the Iacon Hall of Records in the winning days of the war for Cybertron,
当我们在塞博特恩内战中取得优势之时 我们占领了铁堡的档案馆
we acquired highly classified files
从那里得到了一些高度机密文件
which we were not able to decipher.
我们无法破译
It's 'Cons!
是虎子！
And they're busting into the same military research lab they hit two months ago.
他们又闯进了两个月前他们袭击过的军用实验室
We let them finish building their Space-bridge.
我们让他们造好太空桥
Why?
为什么？
So we can commandeer it.
好让我们去接管它
And use it to send me to Cybertron.
用它把我送到塞博特恩去
I have not seen him aboard the ship.
但我却没在船上看到他
Commander Starscream is dead.
红蜘蛛指挥官已经牺牲了
Optimus Prime?!
擎天柱？
Please!
别这样！
I mean no harm!
我没有恶意！
Oh! Then what are you doing here?!
哦！那你在这里做什么？！
Research. For Lord Megatron.
为威震天陛下进行调查
Is this some kind of joke?
你在拿我寻开心吗？
I... do not understand.
我…不明白
And why did you call me "Optimus Prime"?
还有你为什么叫我擎天柱？
Why wouldn't I?
为什么不能叫？
Because my name is Orion Pax.
因为我的名字是奥里安・派克斯
I am far from being a Prime.
我离当领袖还差得远呢
You reminded me of someone I once knew. That's all.
你让我想起了一个老相识 就是这样
You are Starscream.
你是红蜘蛛
...Yes.
…是的
Lord Megatron told me you had been... terminated.
威震天陛下告诉我你已经…光荣捐躯了
Lord Megatron says many things, only some of which are true.
威震天陛下说话一向不太靠谱
You... do not suggest that our leader would speak falsehoods?
你…不会是在暗示我们的首领说谎吧？
You truly are being kept in the dark, aren't you?
你不会真的被蒙在鼓里了吧？
You speak in many riddles, Starscream.
你的话着实令我费解 红蜘蛛
Please, tell me what it is that you know.
请告诉我你都知道些什么
And in return...
作为回报…
Starscream! Surrender!
投降吧！红蜘蛛！
Hold your fire!
别开枪！
Remain in the lab.
老实呆在实验室里
But I...
但是我…
Lord Megatron's orders.
这是威震天陛下的命令
Rafael! Is the test subject ready?
拉斐尔！实验对象都准备好了么？
Check!
完毕！
Long-range GPS activated.
远程GPS已启动
I have doubts whether my recalibrations have successfully  extended Ground-bridge range.
不知二次校准能否将其成功地延伸至环陆桥范围
But there's only one way to find out.
只有一种方法来验证
Come on!
来吧！
It was just the first try...
这只不过是首次测试
No, Rafael. It was pure folly.
不 拉斐尔 这太蠢了
A misguided act of desperation.
这是绝望下的荒唐之举
It takes eons to master Space-bridge engineering.
掌握太空桥工程需要花费一辈子的时间
And no one is more accomplished than the Decepticons...
没有人比霸天虎更了解它…
You know, there is this thing in gym class where you have to climb a rope.
你知道么 这就像在体育课上爬绳子
All the way to the ceiling.
要一直爬到上面
It's really hard.
这真的很难
And I've never been able to do it.
我从未成功过
But...
不过…
When I told Bee about it
当我告诉小蜂的时候
he believed in me.
他相信我能行
Which made me practice a ton.
在鼓励之下 我反复地练习
Finally, just a couple of weeks ago,
最终 仅仅几周之后
I made it! To the top.
我成功地爬上去了
What does any of this have to do with gym class?!
这和体育课有关系么？
I... I was just...
我…我只是…
I'll give you some alone time.
让你一个人静静吧
Optimus... I am so sorry.
擎天柱…我很抱歉
Orion.
奥利安
I am so sorry for the recent commotion.
我对最近的骚动表示抱歉
You weren't in any way harmed, were you?
你没有受伤吧？
No, Lord Megatron.
没有 威震天陛下
But why did you tell me Starscream was dead?
但你为什么对我说红蜘蛛死了？
Because he is dead to our cause.
因为他不再追寻我们的事业了
Starscream was my most trusted lieutenant.
红蜘蛛曾是我最信任的副官
Until he turned traitor and joined the Autobots.
直到他成为叛徒 加入了汽车人
Never have I witnessed a more profound act of deceit.
这是我经历过的最刻骨铭心的背叛
He did not do or say anything troubling to you?
他没对你说什么蛊惑人心的言论吧？
No.
没有
Good.
这就好
Perhaps it's best to forget the entire incident
最好忘记这些琐事
and return to your project.
回到工作上吧
As you wish, my Lord.
遵命 我的陛下
Orion was never very adept at the art of deception.
奥利安永远都不会懂得欺骗的艺术
I made a mistake not terminating Starscream when I had the opportunity.
我犯了一个错误 没能当机立断地宰了红蜘蛛
A mistake I do not intend to make again!
这是我绝不会再犯的错误！
No sign of energon spikes.
没有能量的迹象
Arcee or Bee find the Space-bridge?
阿尔茜和小蜂找到太空桥了么？
They haven't yet reported back.
他们还没有什么消息
Ratchet. You alright?
救护车 你还好么？
Hm? Yes!
嗯？我很好！
Yes. Let's just get you to the next quadrant.
好 我们进行下一步行动
What is it?
这是什么？
A high-frequency signal.
一个高频信号
With an embedded message!
内含一个加密的信息
... for me.
…给我的
Optimus?
是擎天柱？
Starscream.
是红蜘蛛
"I have obtained information regarding your Leader.
我得到了关于你们领袖的情报
Bring medical kit. Come alone".
带上医疗箱 一个人来
I told you to come alone!
我告诉过你要一个人来！
And since when do we listen to you?
我们什么时候开始非得听你的了？
Where is Optimus?
擎天柱在哪儿？
Patch me up and perhaps I'll tell you.
把我修好 或许我会告诉你
Have sympathy. I'm leaking here!
发发慈悲吧 我的能量在泄漏！
Then I suggest that you speak quickly!
那你就快说
Has Optimus been harmed in any way?!
擎天柱有没有受到伤害？！
He's fine. Fine!
他很好 非常好！
Can't you see I'm the one who's been harmed?
你没看见我才是被伤害的那一个么？
Where is he?!
他在哪儿？！
Where do you think?!
那你认为他还能在哪儿？！
He's on Megatron's warship!
当然在威震天的战舰上！
Which is located Where?
具体位置呢？
Ha... ha. Now, who knows?
哼…啊 现在谁知道
It's a ship! It moves.
那是艘飞船！会动！
It took me months to track only to get fired upon.
我追踪了它几个月换来的只有这一身的枪子
You wouldn't go to the trouble of calling me here,
你不会自讨麻烦叫我来的
unless you had information to trade.
除非你有可以用来交换的情报
... real information!
…真正的情报！
Very well...
很好…
Your beloved Leader may have lost his senses.
你挚爱的领袖丧失了自我意识
He goes by the name "Orion Pax" now.
他现在是奥利安・派克斯
And it seems Megatron has led him to believe he's a Decepticon.
看起来威震天让他相信自己成了一个霸天虎！
Tell us something we don't know.
说些我们不知道的吧
What?!
什么？！
How could you possibly know that?!
你们怎么知道这些的？！
We are wasting our time.
我们在浪费时间
Wait. That's all I have! Really!
等等！这是我知道的全部了！真的！
You can't just leave me like this!
你不能把我扔在这里！
Unless you know where Megatron is hiding his Space-bridge,
除非你知道威震天把他的太空桥藏在何处
you can stay here and rust.
不然你就留在这里等着生锈吧
Space-bridge...
太空桥…
Do you mean to tell me that they actually finished building it without my supervision?!
你的意思是说 他们在没有我指导的情况下完成了？！
... it hurts most right here, Doctor.
…这才是最戳我痛处的地方 医生
The Decepticons' Space-bridge is located right here.
霸天虎的太空桥就在这里
Deep within an Energon mine.
在一个能量矿的深处
Adjacent to a raw fuel supply. Clever.
紧靠原始能量供给 很聪明
What's our intel?
哪里来的消息
A... reliable source.
一个…可靠的来源
So! Do we have a consensus?
那么！我们达成共识了么？
Do we know if people can even breathe your atmosphere?
你知道人类能在那里的大气层下呼吸么？
I'll back Jack up.
这个我能帮杰克
Completely, state of the art.
搞到最先进的宇航服
I still have connections at NASA.
我在国家航天局有熟人
It's too dangerous.
这太危险了
Mom. I know that this is hard.
妈妈 我知道这很困难
But Optimus risked his life to save our planet.
但擎天柱冒着生命危险来拯救我们的星球
And he's not even human. We owe it to him.
他甚至不是人类 我们欠他的
Jack may be the only one who can do this, June.
杰克可能是唯一能做到的人 琼
But I don't want you to think for one moment that I'll allow him to travel unchaperoned.
但不要误会 我不会让杰克孤身前往的
Not everyone is destined for an ordinary life.
不是每个人都注定平凡一生
Optimus Prime was once Orion Pax, after all.
擎天柱以前也不过是奥利安・派克斯
When you were little, you always wanted to be an astronaut.
小时候你一直希望能当个宇航员
Okay. "Optimus Prime".
好吧 擎天柱
"Optimus Prime. Leader of the Autobot invaders."
擎天柱 汽车人侵略者的匪首
I reminded Starscream of him?
红蜘蛛看到我时想到了他？
And Lord Megatron said Ratchet was the Autobot leader.
而威震天陛下说救护车才是汽车人的领袖
... someone is not telling the truth.
…有人在说谎
We will ground-bridge directly in to the energon mine
我们将用环陆桥到达能量矿
and make our way to the Space-bridge chamber
杀出一条通往控制室的路
neutralize any Decepticon forces we encounter.
扫清遇到的一切霸天虎障碍
Once we secure the Space-bridge
一旦我们控制了太空桥
we'll send for Jack.
就叫杰克过来
Stealth must be an absolute priority.
行动必须绝对隐秘
We will most certainly be outnumbered
我们很可能寡不敌众
and if any Decepticon should transmit an alert to their warship...
如果有一个霸天虎向战舰报了信…
The odds become four hundred to one.
就会变成四百比一的局面
Scrambling communications upon entry
就这一点而言
will certainly provide an edge in this regard.
干扰通讯系统会为我们的行动提高胜算
Taking the Bridge is the easy part.
占领太空桥还不是最难的
You three need to hold it long enough for Jack and me
你们三个还要撑足够长的时间
to get to Cybertron and back.
直到我和杰克从塞博特恩回来
Rafael climbed to the top of the rope in gym class - we can do this.
拉斐尔在体育课上能爬到绳子的顶端 我们也能行
What does gym class has to do with anything?
这和体育课有关系吗？
And if Ratchet gets to go on a commando raid,
如果救护车要搞突袭
I'm going too.
我也去
Miko. You will help Rafael operate our Ground-bridge
神子 你能帮助拉斐尔操作我们的环陆桥
and manage the communications hub.
以及管理通信枢纽
Can't go to Cybertron.
不能去塞博特恩！
Can't storm the Decepticon Space-bridge!
又不能占领霸天虎的太空桥！
And nurse Darby will stand-by in case of emergency.
达比护士随时待命以应对紧急状况
Son?
孩子？
It's time to suit up.
该整装出发了
Clear.
无异常
Command! This is Space-bridge control.
总部！这里是太空桥控制中心
We are under attack!
我们被袭击了！
Command! Do you copy...
总部！你们收…？
Going down.
下去吧
By the Allspark!
我的火种源啊
Thank you, Starscream.
谢了 红蜘蛛
Who else would it be?
除了他还有谁
A masterpiece of engineering...
工程学上的杰作…
Operational?
能操作吗？
Fully.
能
Perimeter secured.
该区域已经占领
Now the scary part.
现在是最可怕的部分
I'm shutting down the scrambler in order to contact base and maintain communications through the remainder of the mission.
我关闭了干扰器来保持通信以便完成任务
Strike team to base.
突击小队呼叫基地
Objective secured.
目标已得手
That¡¯s your cue.
该你上场了
Bring me back a souvenir.
给我带个纪念品回来
Sooo... what happens when you have to go to the bathroom?
那个…你如果要去洗手间可怎么办？
Safe journey, son.
注意安全 孩子
Just... go already.
放心…去吧
Optimus needs you.
擎天柱需要你
Locking onto Cybertron.
锁定塞博特恩
You ready?
准备好了么？
Let's do this.
开始吧
I'll leave the Space-bridge portal open in order to eliminate any communication lag over the great distance.
为避免信息延迟我会一直让太空桥保持开启
And make it easier for you to locate when you're ready to return.
也为了你们在回来的时候更容易定位
Easier to locate?
容易定位？
You're not bridging us straight to the Big V?
你不是要用太空桥把我们直接送到魔力神球那里吗？
Vector Sigma's true location is shrouded in myth and rumour, Jack.
魔力神球的真实位置早就被神话跟谣传歪曲了 杰克
It is said that the path of the Primes leads there.
传说领袖之路会通向那里
We must be confident that Optimus will guide you.
我们要坚信擎天柱会引导你的
Don't worry. Space-bridging is just like Ground-bridging.
别担心 太空桥和环陆桥没什么大的区别
Just a little more intense!
就是稍微有点刺激
I... I can't believe it!
我…我真不敢相信
I am actually on another planet.
我竟然在另一个星球上
Arcee, this is incredible!
阿尔茜 这太难以置信了！
Arcee?
阿尔茜？
This isn't how I wanted you to see my home.
我不想让你看到我的家乡是这番景象
I'm... I'm sorry.
我…我很抱歉
In the fog of war it is hard to see beyond the next leg of the mission
在战争的迷雾中我们只能看到下一个任务
or the next punch in the fight.
或者下一场战斗 难有远见卓识
We did everything to save Cybertron.
我们竭尽全力只为挽救塞博特恩
But when the fog finally lifted...
当迷雾散去时…
There wasn't much left to save.
已经剩不下什么可挽救的了
Arcee! Jack! Do you copy?
阿尔茜！杰克！你收到了么？
Roger. We're on Cybertron.
救护车 我们在塞博特恩上
- Yes! - Woo-hoo!
- 好哇！ - 呀哈！
Oh, thank goodness!
感谢上帝！
Just keep the sightseeing to a minimum, huh.
别只顾着观光 呃？
Indeed. We don't know if your journey ahead is 5 kliks or 5000.
没错 我们不知道要走5公里还是500公里
Understood.
明白
We're out.
我们出发吧
Okay. Ratchet said the Card would guide us, but...
好吧 救护车说钥匙芯片会引导我 但是…
I don't see how or what I'm supposed to...
我不知道如何 或是怎样去…
There you go.
就去那边
This could be awhile.
这得好一阵子呢
Space-Bridge Control, do you read me?
太空桥控制中心 你收到了吗？
Space-bridge control, this is Breakdown.
太空桥控制中心 我是打击
Your status report is overdue.
你没有按时汇报情况
Scrap.
糟了
Bulkhead, no! He'll recognize your voice.
隔板 别 他会认出你的声音
I can make it lower.
我能把频率变低
Higher?
或是调高呢?
He would recognize mine as well.
他也会认出我的
Come in, Space-bridge Control!
回话 太空桥控制中心！
Don't make me come down and dent some engine blocks.
别逼我下去爆了你的气缸
Somebody say something, pronto!
有人得说点什么 要快！
Rafael! Patch in Agent Fowler.
拉斐尔！让福勒探员上
You have one nanocycle to respond or!..
你有一微循环的时间来报告 不然…
This is Space-bridge Control. Situation normal.
这里是太空桥控制中心 一切正常
Normal? You sure about that?
正常？你确定？
We were just... calibrating the subsystems and we, uh,
我们就是…校准了一下系统 我们还…
had a surge, but it's fine now.
呃 有点小问题 但现在好了
How are you?
你那边好么？
Er, erm... Never better!
呃 嗯…再好不过了！
I know it¡¯s thankless down there.
我知道在下面干活不容易
Keep up the good work. Huh?
好好干吧
Will do. Control out.
我们会的 通话结束
Why would the Decepticon archive be so heavily encrypted?
为什么霸天虎档案馆的加密如此复杂
How could I possibly be "Optimus Prime"?
我怎么可能是擎天柱？
Even our encryptions couldn't keep him from the truth!
就算是我们层层加密也无法让他远离真相
Orion has much to accomplish and he will stay the course!
奥利安还有许多任务 他会坚持到底的！
Even if I must inflict great pain to ensure the completion of project "Iacon"!
哪怕我得给他施加巨大的痛苦也要完成铁堡计划！
That way.
这边走
Toward Kaon?
去卡隆？
The Decepticon capital. Swell.
霸天虎的首都 好极了
We're on foot from here.
我们从这里开始步行
Don¡¯t want engine noise to attract the wrong kind of attention.
我不想让引擎声招来不必要的注意
'Cons?
虎子？
Vermin.
害虫
This way.
这边走